# **Pengfan Zhang**

New York, NY 10001 | 9172397253 | pz723@nyu.edu | LinkedIn | GitHub

## **Summary**

Detail-oriented junior at New York University, experienced in web design and front-end development, active team-player, confident in software and programming skills, with passion in tech field. Actively looking for software engineer internship.

• Programming Languages

Java (3 yrs), HTML (1 yr), CSS (1 yr), JavaScript (1 yr), C (1 yr)

Software Skills

GitHub, MS Office, MS Visual Studio Code, MongoDB Compass, Postman

Fast Learner

Self-learned the new frameworks NuxtJs, Vuetify, and applied to web development to improve coding efficiency, receiving praise from the team leader

Communication

Effectively communicate and presented projects to teammates

### **Education**

**New York University** 

New York, NY

Expected May 2023

**Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics and Computer Science** Cumulative GPA: 3.91/4.00 Honor: Dean's List (2019-2021)

Relevant Courses: Intro to Web Design, Data Structure, Computer System Organization, Basic Algorithm, Software Engineering,

Object Oriented Programming **Internship Experience** 

US Cabinet Depot | Software Engineer | Kennesaw, GA

Jun. 2021 – Aug. 2021

- Developed a new e-commerce and marketing website with 3 teammates and updated the latest progress to team leader individually per week
- Applied framework Nuxt.js and Vuetify to design responsive layout of marketing page and customer check out page
- Separated front-end codes and content data from marketing pages to improve efficiency of informational page-updating

**Project Experience** 

**Smart Choice** Sept. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Agilely developed a web app with 5 teammates to help NYU students plan their courses
- Created site map and wireframe diagrams by draw.io and InVision, built straightforward user interface for browsing courses and student comments with ReactJs, fetched NYU's course catalog data and communicate with database in ExpressJs and stored user's comments, ratings, and course selections with MongoDB and JWT Authentication
- Deployed the web app on centOS in Digital Ocean Droplet used by 30 users and receive positive feedback from professor

## Carbonology, TreeHacks 2021

Feb. 2021

- Brainstormed themes of a Web APP with 3 teammates, researched 2 APIs and created the APP demo in 48 hours
- Used ReactJs to enable numerical data and links uploads, processed uploads by Carbon Interface API and Clarifai API
- Designed user interface for computers and mobile devices using Bootstrap and CSS, received and displayed the calculated result

#### **College Info. Station**

Jan. 2021

- Developed website for searching general information of universities and colleges in the U.S.
- Utilized ReactJs to support retrieved data through College Scorecard API, visualized the numerical data by React Minimal Pie Chart Package
- Designed user interface by Bootstrap, and displayed results with animation and illustrations
- Published the website and got 172 users according to Google Analytics

#### **MLA Citation Format Generator**

Dec. 2020 – Jan. 2021

- Individually developed a website to edit academic citations in MLA format, designed user interface by CSS
- Utilized HTML, JavaScript to upload information or ISBN number, processed ISBN input by Google Book API, and generated citations and published the <a href="website">website</a>, used by 122 users base on Google Analytics

MineSweeper Game Nov. 2019

- Utilized Java to create a mine sweeper game, implemented functions of left clicking and right clicking with responses
- Applied graphical library to process the interface of unopened and opened cells, flags, and ending scene; shared the demo to 20+
  classmates with an A as a result

## **Campus Involvement**

**New York University** | *Grader* 

Sept. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Collaborated with other 9 graders to grade Basic Algorithm homework from 108 students per week based on the rubric
- Communicated with Professor Alan Siegel and course assistant by Email for selecting the best student answer as example

## Intl. Dept., the Affiliated High School of SCNU | Group Leader

Dec. 2017 – Jan. 2018

- Led a group of 15 to purchase ingredients and prepare the food beforehand
- Assigned members into 4 groups to sell homemade Spanish foods and drinks on the International Day, raised \$100+ and donated to the Guangzhou Social Welfare Institute